《开心汉堡店》第五季第八集
翻译：小布拿拿      Tiogy      红豆包      斯人
有没有很鼠昂[爽]
除虫害公司
翻译&校对&总监：Iz
后期：斯人     时间轴：深夏桃子
孩子们  今天想不想欣赏件
Kids, before you go to school,
艺术品再去上学
you want to see some art?
我今天已经在镜子里见过了  所以不用了
I've already looked in the mirror once today, so I am good.
是在搞什么把戏吗
Is this a trick?
我们说想  你就给我们看你的光屁股
We say "Sure" and then you moon us?
不  你们知道那位
No. You know that customer
总是在纸巾上涂鸦的客人吧
who always doodles on his napkins?
看看他昨天画了什么
Look what he drew yesterday.
是个钓鱼的人
Oh. It's a fisherman.
他把油迹当成湖水
And he used the grease stain as a lake.
用的真是巧妙
That's a good use of grease.
知道吗  也许我们该把它挂起来
You know what, maybe we should put it up over here.
搞一个顾客涂鸦墙
Start a wall of customer drawings, right?
纸巾涂鸦墙
A wall of napkin art.
真是个好主意  琳
That's a good idea, Lin.
是个好主意  老妈
It is a good idea, Mom.
但你知道你哪做的不好吗
But you know what isn't?
你把咖啡杯放在了柜台的桌沿
Putting your coffee mug so close to the edge of the counter.
那可是杯滚烫的咖啡啊
That's a piping hot cup of ouch.
多谢提醒  蒂娜
Thank you, Tina.
我们知道  你是过道巡视员
We get it. You're a hall monitor.
你还是去学校发光发热吧
Leave your work at school.
抱歉  但我的努力都会得到回报
Sorry. But all my hall monitoring is gonna pay off.
我想福旺德老师打算提升我为
I think Mr. Frond is about to promote me
最高级别的过道巡视员
to the highest hall monitor rank there is.
蒂娜升职仪式
也就是"海牛"级别
It's called Hall Manatee.
海牛  为什么叫这个
Hall Manatee? Why is it called that?
有两种说法
There are two schools of thought about that.
-不  别说了  我不想听  -好吧
- No, never mind. I don't want to hear. - Okay.
你好  尔珀小姐
Hi, Ms. Selbo.
来为过道巡视员工作签到的吗
Signing in for hall monitor duty?
你知道吗  传闻
You know, there's a rumor going around
你将晋升高职
that you're up for a big promotion.
不要听信那些传闻  尔珀小姐
Oh, don't listen to rumors, Ms. Selbo.
那我还有什么可做的
Then what would I do?
接电话吗
Just answer the phone when it rings?
蒂娜  得了吧
Tina, come on.
给你的背心
Here's your vest.
祝你好运 海牛蒂娜
Good luck, Mana-Tina.
什么  我居然没给你说过
What? You didn't hear it from me.
你好  蒂娜  我先帮你签好了
Hi, Tina. I-I went ahead and signed you in.
你真细心  但帮他人签到
That was thoughtful, Rudy, but it's against the rules
是违反规定的
to forge a signature on the sign-in sheet.
对哦  还有规则
Oh, yeah. The rules.
我想是我太散漫了
I guess I played it pretty fast and loose.
抖臀的时候才需要
Yeah, let's save fast and loose for
散漫[快而灵活]
when you shake your caboose.
-规矩就是用来遵守的  -是的  抱歉
- Rules were made to be followed. - Right, sorry.
看  你当选海牛是有道理的
See, that's why you're gonna be a Hall Manatee
瓦格斯塔夫小学"过道巡视员"级别
海牛
枪鱼
鲦鱼
而我只能做个"鲦鱼"
and I'm stuck at Hall Minnow.
还有一个原因是我不懂得疏通人脉
Well, I'm also a Hall Minnow 'cause I'm bad at networking.
第三轮巡视  离午饭时间还有四十分钟
Third period. Lunch is 40 minutes away.
学生都又饿又狂躁
Kids are hungry and cranky,
也就意味着  在过道上
which means out in the hallway
-什么事都有可能发生  -明白了
- anything can happen. - Got it.
你慢点
Oh, slow you didn't.
我是说你在过道里没有放慢速度
I'm saying you weren't going slow in the hall.
你能慢点吗
Slow you didn't?
我应该表达得更清楚些  抱歉
I should have been more clear. Sorry.
你的全名和年级
Full name and grade?
丹尼・杜金斯基  五年级
Danny Duszynski, fifth.
杜金斯基  多谢  丹尼
Duszynski. Thank you, Danny.
傻逼...
You stupid...
你说什么
What's that?
再见  谢谢
Bye. Thank you.
不用谢
You're welcome.
他说脏话
He used language.
不  我想他说的是"谢谢"
No, I think he just said "Thank you."
蒂娜  我直接说吧  你是我的榜样
Tina, can I just say it? You inspire me.
我知道
I know.
等等  我听那声音耳熟
Hold on. I recognize that sound.
是屁股摩擦金属的声音
It's butts on brass.
跟我来
Follow me.
我爱地心引力
I love gravity!
幸好我穿了我的抗荷裤
I'm glad I wore my fast pants!
抗荷服  一般为飞行员所穿  在加速度过高情况下
能提高抗正载能力的服装
-你们刚把自己滑成留校生了  -说得好
- Hey, guys. You just slid into detention. - Nice.
我需要知道你们的全名和年级
I'm gonna need a full name and grade from both of you.
我知道  想吓我们是吧  蒂娜
I get it. Good psych-out, Tina.
好怕怕哦
You scared us straight.
全名和年级
Uh, full name and grade.
我不能告诉你我的全名
I can't tell you my full name!
老妈不告诉我我的中间名字  你知道的
You know Mom won't tell me my middle name!
我去  蒂娜  你谁啊
Geez, Tina, what are you,
烦人鬼和告状精么
Narcy Narc and the Narcy Bunch?
好吧  露易丝和吉恩・贝尔彻
Fine. Louise and Gene Belcher.
好了  上课去
All right, off to class.
家里见
And I'll see you at home.
今晚老妈要做什么呢  有人知道吗
What's Mom making tonight? Anyone know?
聊得很愉快
Good talk.
真是不留情面啊
That was cold-blooded.
看来一旦成为过道巡视员
I guess when you're a hall monitor
就得把私人感情关进柜子里啊
you have to leave your feelings in your locker.
-还把密码给忘了  -这样啊
- And lose the combination. - Yeah...
正在执行任务的过道巡视员
Hall monitors on duty,
请立即到布莱文斯教官办公室报到
report immediately to Coach Blevins' office.
我们走
Let's move.
放我走  见鬼
Let me go. Dang.
齐克  你叫我们吗  福旺德老师
Zeke. You called us, Mr. Frond?
蒂娜  我的明星巡视员
Tina. My star hall monitor.
还有中号鲁迪
And Regular Sized Rudy.
有待提高的巡视员
My fixer-upper hall monitor.
我会努力的
I'll get there.
我从课堂上回来
Anyway, I stepped away from class
取我的防震防护镜
to retrieve my shatterproof sports goggles...
酷毙了
Suh-weet.
多谢  当我来到办公室
Thanks. When I got to my office,
发现齐克在这鬼鬼鬼祟祟的
I found Zeke in here digging around.
擅自闯入老师的办公室
Trespassing in a teacher's office.
你被三振出局了  齐克
This is strike three for you, Zeke.
这意味着你将自动被停学
I'm afraid that means automatic suspension.
但是我有很好的理由
But I got a good reason.
省省吧  蒂娜  你押送齐克
Save it. Tina, I need you to escort Zeke
去校长办公室
to the principal's office.
我本可以亲自送  但我手机掉厕所里了
I'd do it myself, but I dropped my cell phone in the toilet,
我得马上把它放进米桶里
and I need to put it in rice immediately.
有人这么试过吗  有用吗
Has anyone tried that? Does it work?
这下福旺德老师的手机变"臭"机啦
Mr. Frond's got a smell phone.
你被停学了
You're suspended.
蒂娜  你觉得你能办好这事吗
Tina, think you can handle this?
我认为你不太清楚
I don't think you can handle
我多擅长这个  福旺德老师
how much I can handle this, Mr. Frond.
我们走吧  齐克
Let's go, Zeke.
接下来交给我了  鲁迪
I'll take it from here, Rudy.
你的任务完成了
You finish your rounds.
你确定吗  齐克可不好对付
Are you sure? Zeke's trouble.
就是个午间小差  我闭着眼都能做好
It's a midday run. I could do it in my sleep.
好吧  但我想帮忙
Yeah, but I want to help.
我从来没押送过罪犯
I've never transported a perp.
不用了  鲁迪
Yeah, we're good, Rudy.
蒂娜给鲁迪耍威风了
Tina's giving Rudy some 'tude-y.
闭嘴  齐克  抱歉  我不该这么说
Shut up, Zeke. I'm sorry I said "Shut up."
你闭嘴吧
You shut up.
看泰迪画的  多酷炫
Look what Teddy did! Funky pattern.
我挂起来
I'm putting it up!
螺旋图案超酷对吧
Spirals, right?
欢迎来到我的内心世界
Welcome to my brain.
琳达  看我画的
Look at mine, Linda.
是戴着太阳镜的太阳
It's a sun wearing sunglasses.
有人很呆萌嘛
Someone's feeling silly.
被你发现啦
Guilty!
给  我画的
Here you go. Here's mine.
-这是个啥  -是张脸
- What is it? - It's a face.
我认不出来
I don't recognize it.
画的不是某个人
Well, it's no one in particular.
就是一张脸
It's just a face.
能看成脚吗
Could it be a foot?
我看出来了
Oh, I see it now!
一张很漂亮的脸
It's a beautiful face.
那你会放墙上去吗
So are you gonna put it on the wall?
啥  当然
What? Yeah. S-Sure.
当然
Yeah, of cour...
我会放上去的
I'm gonna put it up.
-墙上  -你看起来好像不大想
- Wall. - Well, it doesn't seem like you want to.
这里有个空位  正好
Oh, here's a spot for it. Right there.
琳  你把它放咖啡壶后面了
Wait. Y... Lin, you're putting it behind the coffee machine.
-是吗  -算了
- Am I? - Forget it.
如果你不喜欢
If...I-I don't want you to put it up
-我也不想你挂上去  -好吧
- if you don't like it. - Okay.
好险  差点以后每次咖啡壶
That was close. We were gonna have to look
被拿起来  我们都要看到那玩意了
at that thing every time they moved the coffee pot.
对不住了  泰迪  我画不出螺旋图案
Sorry, Teddy. Sorry it's not a spiral
和戴太阳镜的太阳是我的错
or a sun with sunglasses.
说到螺旋图案
Speaking of spirals...
-不错吧  -酷炫到晕眩
- Right? - Oh, I'm dizzy!
又来一张咯
Another one's going up!
-真是够了  -放那里
- Oh, my God. - Put it... put it right there.
喂  犯罪时间不吻合
Come on! The time doesn't fit the crime.
快放了我
You got to let me go!
够了齐克  你就是
Enough, Zeke. You're the one
闯入体育老师办公室的凶手
who broke into the gym teacher's office.
好吧  但其实我是为了我奶奶
Okay, listen, I did it for my grandma.
说的跟真的似的
Sure you did.
那你把我交上去之前
Well, can I at least
我能去上个厕所吗
use the bathroom before you turn me in?
-不行  -拜托
- I don't think so. - Please!
蒂娜  有点同情心好不好
Have a heart, Tina! Good gosh.
好吧  不过尽快
Okay. But make it quick.
知道了  谢了  小蒂妞
All right! Thanks, T-Bird!
好吧
Okay.
齐克  作为过道巡视员  我命令你
Zeke? Zeke, as your hall monitor, I'm ordering you:
即刻出来  记得洗手
Come out with your hands washed.
真奇怪
That's odd.
有人在吗
Anybody in here?
我进来90%是为了公务
I'm coming in on 90% official hall monitor business.
10%是因为好奇心  齐克
And 10% curiosity. Zeke?
回答我  我知道你在
Answer me, Zeke. I know you're in there.
我看到你的鞋了
I can see your shoes.
你的腿呢
Where'd your legs go?
怎么  不好
What the... Oh, no.
齐克跑了
I lost Zeke.
-蒂娜  -福旺德老师
- Tina. - Mr. Frond.
怎么样了  齐克有给你添乱吗
How'd it go? Did Zeke give you any trouble?
想也知道
Of course he did.
不过我相信你解决好了对吗
But I'm sure you handled it, right?
蒂娜  蒂娜
Tina? Tina?
蒂娜  这声音听得我难受
God, that sound makes me queasy, Tina.
一切顺利
It went great.
我带他去了校长那里
I dropped him off at the principal,
校长说
and the principal said,
"谢谢你蒂娜"  一切如常  -很好
- "Thank you, Tina." Everything was fine. - Terrific.
所以说你是最佳嘛
That's why you're the best.
别哼哼了
Stop it!
蒂娜
Tina.
骗子
Liar.
齐克
Zeke.
齐克  出来
Zeke. Come out.
大家都在玩摔跤哦
Everyone's... wrestling out here.
-我被摔了  -蒂娜
- I'm being wrestled. - Oh, hey, Tina.
抱歉打扰了
Sorry to interrupt.
齐克的事还顺利吗
Everything okay with Zeke?
很顺利
Everything's fine.
怎么突然问这个
What a weird thing to bring up.
好啦  我是中号鲁迪啊
Come on. It's Regular Sized Rudy.
你什么都可以告诉我的
You can talk regular to me.
都很好  鲁迪
Everything is great, Rudy!
-很好很好很好  -但是
- It's really, really, really, really great! - Okay, but...
-我感觉  -得走了
- it just seem... - Got to go.
都很好  回见
Everything's great. See you soon.
真不敢相信
I can't believe it.
我的英雄变坏了
My hero's gone dirty.
冷静
Stand down, feelings.
Stand down.
该我出动挽救一切了
Time for Rudy to clean up this mess.
要到午饭时间了
It's almost lunchtime.
等人一来
Once these halls fill up with people,
就不可能找到齐克了
I'll never find Zeke.
我得找后援
I should call for backup.
课上就把我们叫出来有什么事
Why'd you pull us out of class?
就是啊  我还在学习呢
Yeah, I was learning stuff!
我需要你们帮忙
You guys, I need your help.
是吗  你今天可查了我们水表
Oh, do you? You busted us today
好像我们只是两个滑扶手的陌生人
like we were just a couple of butt-sliding strangers!
就是  我们可是从一个子宫
Yeah! We all slid out of
滑出来的  老姐
the same place, sister!
又不是针对你们
It was nothing personal.
那好  我们也不是针对你
Well, then nothing personal,
想要我们帮忙
but if you want our help,
可得好好补偿
it's gonna cost you big-time!
好吧好吧  给你们每人一张通行证
Yeah! Ok-Okay, I-I can give you each a hall pass.
就这样  那算了
Is that all? Then we will pass on that offer.
等等  那给你们
Wait! What if I could give you...
永久通行证呢
a permanent hall pass?
永久通行证  真的有吗
A perma-pass? Is that real?
有吗  一张通行证走天下
Could it be? One hall pass to rule them all.
有的  不过仅限
It exists, but only for kids
身体状况不好的学生使用
with serious medical conditions.
-太棒  -只要我们帮你晋升
- Lucky! - So we help you get promoted...
-走道就随你们浪了  -很好
And these halls are yours. All right.
有点意思  要帮你什么忙
You got our attention. What's the job?
齐克不见了  我该把他带去办公室的
I lost Zeke. I was supposed to get him to the office,
但他逃走了  我需要你们帮我找到他
but he got away. I need you to help me get him back.
就这样啊  蒂娜  动动脑
Is that all? Think, Tina.
要怎么找一个不想被找到的人呢
How do you find someone who doesn't want to be found?
对那个人的朋友下手
You rough up that someone's friend.
小吉米  我觉得不应该
Jimmy Jr.? Oh, I don't think we need to ask him
-去问他  -你不想找齐克吗
- anything about this. - Want to get Zeke?
那就硬着头皮也得上  阿蒂
Then suck it up, T.
小吉  兄弟  怎么样啊
J-Ju! Buddy! What's going on, man?
露易丝  你想干嘛
What do you want, Louise?
我想干嘛  就是聊聊
What do I want? I want to chat.
帮我看着食堂大妈和巡逻的人
Watch for lunch ladies and Feds.
-好了  他在哪儿  -谁在哪儿
- All right, where is he? - Where is who?
你的朋友齐克  他躲在学校什么地方了
Your buddy Zeke. He's hiding somewhere in school.
我啥都不知道
I-I don't know anything about it.
是吗  告诉我  你是跳舞的
Oh, no? Tell me something. You're a dancer.
脚趾对舞者有多重要
How important is it for a dancer to have toes?!
-露易丝  不疼  -怎么可能
- That didn't hurt, Louise. - Why not?!
我用了全身的力气
That was my whole body!
因为我穿了厚袜子
I'm wearing thick socks?
好  那把袜子脱了
Okay. Take your socks off.
-不要  -齐克去哪了  小吉米
- No. - Where's Zeke, Jimmy Jr.?!
-哎呀  -我告诉你妹了  蒂娜
- Yikes. - I told your sister, Tina,
-我不知道  -这回答不够好
- I don't know. - That's not good enough.
蒂娜  这餐盘好恶心
Tina, this tray is gross!
谁让你在杂烩汤日这天骗我
Too bad you chose chowder day to lie to me.
今天是杂烩汤日吗
It's chowder day?
好吧  我不确定
Okay! I don't know for sure,
但齐克经常去一个地方
but there's a place Zeke goes sometimes.
他称为藏身洞
He calls it his hidey-hole.
-在哪里  -住手  蒂娜
- Where is it? - Stop it, Tina!
储藏室
The storage room!
科学实验室那边
Over by the science lab!
现在脱掉你的袜子
Now take off your socks!
对  脱掉袜子
Yeah, take off your socks!
好吧
Okay!
等等
Oh, wait.
别脱袜子了
don't take off your socks.
穿上吧  抱歉
Put them back on. Sorry.
对  也没什么意义了
Yeah, it wouldn't make much sense.
等下  是穿上还是
Wait, so put 'em back on or...
穿上
Put it back on!
好吧
Okay!
快点  快点
Faster! Faster!
穿不上去了
It's not going on!
穿上  现在
Put them on! Now!
全是汗
They're all sweaty!
好了  这边加一点阴影
Okay. A little shading over here.
看起来不错  琳  来看看
Looks good. Uh, Lin, take a look.
我又画了一幅
I did another one.
我还是用回了画图板
I went back to the drawing board. Literally.
我  我画了个
And I... and I drew something
我绝对不会画糟的  汉堡
I know I could never mess up-- a burger.
嗯啊  挺好的
Yeah. It's good.
天哪  你连演戏都不会
Oh, my God. You are so bad at pretending you like it.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
画得真好  我都想吃了
It's so good I want to eat it.
看  我刚吃了
Look, I just ate it.
好  我们把它挂上  我们会挂上的
Okay, let's put it up. We'll put it up.
不  琳  我不要你同情才挂
No, Lin, I-I don't want a sympathy hang.
你到底喜不喜欢
Do you like it or not?
邮递员迈克
Mike the Mailman!
快进来  和我们聊聊  拜托
Get in here! Talk to us! Please.
告诉你  别拿迈克当借口
You know what, don't use Mike as an excuse
转移话题  琳
to change the subject, Lin.
什么话题
What was the subject?
-你的婚姻吗  -什么
- Your marriage? - What?
-涂鸦墙啊  -是啊
- Oh, doodle wall, huh? - Yeah!
你觉得怎么样  艺术气吧
What do you think, huh? Artsy.
借一下  搞定  3D方块
May I? Boom. 3-D cube.
-天哪  真是完美  -确实不错
- Oh, my God, it's perfect! - That's good.
真是跃然纸上
Yeah. Oh, it's jumping out at me!
这得贴在墙上
Oh. Oh, it's going on the wall.
你知道秘诀是什么吗
You know what the trick is?
画个正方形  再画一个  连起来
Draw a square, draw another square, connect 'em.
看  你永远想不到
See, you never know.
一个邮差也可以是艺术家
People could be a mailman but they're also an artist.
为什么除了我大家都很在行
Why is everybody good at this but me?!
某人嫉妒了  我很喜欢  迈克
Okay, someone's jealous. I love it, Mike.
这藏身洞不错嘛
This is a good hidey-hole.
这间房需要的是一张桌子
What this room really needs is a desk.
齐克  你在吗
Zeke? You in here?
你从下找  我们往上找
You go low, we'll go high.
-齐克  -看
- Zeke? - Look!
看到他了吗
You see him?
不  是一盒粉笔头
No, it's a box of chalk nubs!
粉笔头派对
Nub party!
齐克  我听到你了
Zeke, I can hear you.
在那  他在那
There! There he is!
出去  蒂娜
Get out, Tina!
你无处可爬了
You have nowhere left to crawl.
我说过了  我是无辜的
I told you, I'm innocent!
我不管
I don't care.
好吧  只能这样做了
All right, only one thing left to do.
一跳换自由
Jump to freedom!
我来了  奶奶
I'm coming, Grandma!
你还是无处可爬
You still have nowhere left to crawl.
这是什么
What is this?
中国手指套
Chinese finger trap.
我参加聚会的纪念品
I got it as a party favor.
-但是是美国的  -好吧
- But in America. - All right.
有什么机关吗
Is there a trick to it?
别告诉我
Don't tell me.
-好吧  告诉我  -不
- Okay, tell me. - No.
你抓到人了  蒂娜
Got your man, Tina.
而我在吃这支粉笔
And I'm eating this chalk.
我们都干得不错
We all did good.
现在都交给我吧  各位
I'll take it from here, guys.
我们的永久通行证呢
What about our perma-passes?
有那种东西么  见鬼
Those exist? Dang!
我听说是要纹在脖子上  超痛
I heard they tattoo 'em on your neck and it hurts,
但也值了
but it's worth it.
不用  但是用复合层压纸做的
No, but they're laminated.
给  要有人问起来
Here. If anyone asks,
就说你们有肠道易激综合症
you have irritable bowel syndrome.
所有的肠子都易激好吗
All bowels are irritable.
你好  通行证  我是露易丝
Hey, ticket to ride. I'm Louise.
我们走吧
Let's roll.
我们去除课堂以外的所有地方吧
Let's go everywhere in the world except class.
好像我越用力扯
It's almost like the harder I pull,
它卡得越紧
the tighter it gets.
在这儿呢
Found you!
-鲁迪  -你对福旺德老师撒谎了
- Rudy! - You lied to Mr. Frond!
你说已经把齐克送到了
You said you delivered Zeke.
我正在送  现在
I am delivering him. Now.
让开  鲁迪
Back off, Rudy.
你曾是我的英雄  现在看看你自己
You were my hero. Now look at you!
-见鬼  -齐克要和我走
- Dang! - Zeke's coming with me.
-淡定  孩子  -松开她  蒂娜
- Easy, squirt. - Detach him, Tina.
我来送齐克
I'm bringing Zeke in,
我还要向福旺德老师举报你
and I'm reporting you to Mr. Frond.
你搞砸了  伙计
You blew it, man.
不  我为这次晋升付出太多
No! I worked too hard for this promotion.
交出齐克
Hand over the Zeke!
午餐结束了  看
Lunch is over. Hey, look,
有个小孩  在做什么危险的事
a kid, uh, doing something dangerous
-破坏了规定  -规定...
- and breaking a rule. - Oh, rules are...
回来
Hey, come back!
你在做什么
What are you doing!
校长室在另一头
The principal's office is the other way.
到校长室可不止一条路
There's more than one way to the principal's office.
有两条
There are two ways.
激情四射画廊
来了
Here we go.
-这个人  -什么
- This guy. - What?!
你好  那个
Hi. Uh, so,
我要报名速成绘画班
I need a quick drawing lesson.
你是说"十万火急"绘画学习套餐吧
Oh, you must mean the Emergency Drawing Package.
是的  有  有那个吗
Yes. D-Do you have that?
不  根本没那种东西
No! 'Cause there's no such thing!
-画家靠的是多年的训练  -多年
- Takes years of training to be an artist. - Years!
听我说  你们是我唯一认识的画家
Look, you're the only real artists I know.
你们很有天赋
You're very talented.
其实  哈罗德没啥天赋
Well, actually, Harold's not that good.
-我  还不错  -并没有  亲爱的
- I'm-I'm fair. - You're not, honey.
-我有  -你自己心里清楚
- I am! - You know you aren't.
好吧
Okay.
听着  我非常希望
Look, I would really appreciate it
你们能帮帮我  我会很荣幸
if you'd help me-- I'd be... honored.
行了  别低三下四的了
All right. Stop groveling!
给你上个速成课吧
We'll give you a crash course.
真的吗  太感谢了
Really? Thank you.
我去工作室准备
I'll set up the studio.
哈罗德  让他买画具
Harold, sell him the supplies.
好的  三十块
All right. $30!
就一支笔和一沓纸
For a pencil and a pad of paper?
-你想不想学画画了  -付钱
- You want to learn to draw?! - Pay the man!
好好好
All right, all right, all right.
快点  我们得绕到
Come on, we just need to get around
学校前面
to the front of the school.
能问个问题吗
Can I ask you something?
你为什么想当过道巡视员啊
Why do you want to be a hall monitor, anyway?
不就是打学生小报告吗
It's just telling on kids.
不是打学生报告
It's not telling on kids.
是帮助学生
It's helping on kids.
你可没有帮到我
Well, you aren't helping on me.
那是你自己的问题
It's your own fault.
你撒谎已经不是第一次了
You've committed a series of Mr. Wieners.
-我把你列为轻犯  -酷
- That's what I call misdemeanors. - Cool.
-这能让你的工作更有趣  -没错
- Funny words make the job fun. - Yeah.
听着  事实是这样的
Listen, this is the truth.
我闯进教练的办公室
I broke into Coach's office
是为了拿扮吉祥物的服装
so I could take the mascot uniform.
瓦格斯塔夫捕鲸者么  为啥
The Wagstaff Whaler? Why?
我说过了  为了我奶奶
I told you-- for my grandma.
她今天要做手术  我只是想
She's having surgery today, and I just wanted
让她进手术室前开心开心
to mascot around for her before she went under the knife.
-你觉得我会信吗  -会啊
- You expect me to believe that? - Yeah.
奶奶们都喜欢吉祥物
Grandma likes mascots.
她和我爷爷就是在大学扮吉祥物认识的
She met my grandpa when they were mascottin' in college.
他俩望着对方傻乎乎的眼睛
They looked into each other's big dumb foam eyes,
就一发不可收拾了
and that was it.
勒邦姿老师  如果她看到我们
Miss Labonz! If she sees us,
咱麻烦就大了
we'll be in big trouble.
你们这俩孩子在外面干什么呢
What are you two kids doing outside?
你在干嘛呢  勒老师
What are you doing, Miss L?
抽烟啊  酷
Smoking. Cool.
抽烟一点都不酷  齐克
Smoking is not cool, Zeke.
-很酷哦  -不  不酷
- Yes, it is. - N-No, it's not.
尤其是老师抽烟  耪ㄌ
Especially when teachers do it. That's cool!
感觉像你在教我抽烟
It's like you're teaching me to smoke.
爱死了
I love this stuff!
别  不准这么说  齐克
Don't... Stop saying that, Zeke.
我们现在是哥们儿了
We're like best friends, man.
才不是
No, we're not.
-不啊  -香烟把我俩联系在一起
- No. - We're bonding over cigarettes.
太棒了
That's pretty cool.
没有的事
We are not bonding over cigarettes!
就有就有
Sure we are.
给我来一根
Hey, hey, let me get one of those!
我早想试一试了
I've been dying to try one of them.
你两快回去上课
You two get to class!
来嘛  给我扔一根
Come on, throw one in my mouth.
-试试我能不能接住  -打住
- I'll see if I can catch it. - Stop.
别和我说话了
Stop talking to me.
搞定
Took care of that.
当你问成年人要烟的时候
Adults get really nervous
他们都会很紧张
when you ask them for cigarettes.
脑子很灵光嘛  谢了
Quick thinking. Thanks.
这才叫帮助别人
That's how you help a kid.
而不是当个纠察队长
Not by being a narc.
那啥  什么情况
Okay, what's happening, exactly?
人体素描  只要画好裸体人像
Life drawing. If you can draw a nude figure,
你就啥都能画了
you can draw anything.
抓起你的炭笔  查理
Grab your charcoal, Charlie!
-女士等着呢  -好吧
- Lady's a-waitin'. - Okay, um,
我  我首先要画什么
wha-what do I draw first?
姿势  神韵
The gesture, and then the essence,
还有胸
and then the breasts.
我没看你画呢
I don't see you drawing!
不好意思  我没法抬眼
Sorry, I can't look up.
哈罗德  帮我看看  他画的如何
Harold, be my eyes-- how's he doing?
-很糟糕  -我在努力了
- Bad. - Listen, I'm trying.
我只是有点呼吸困难
I just can't breathe right now.
你是觉得我不好看吗
Oh, you don't like what you see, huh?
不是啊  挺好的
Oh, it's good. No, it's fine.
你要适应它  这就是人类的形态
Get used to it-- it's the human form.
是你今生所见
It's the most beautiful thing
最美好的事物
you're ever gonna see in your life.
简直秀色可餐
It's super yummy.
-听听  -我只是没想到会有毛
- Tell him! - I just wasn't expecting the hair.
你再不让我走  我就把手指咬下来
If you don't let me go, I'm gonna chew my finger off!
-齐克  -拜托
- Zeke! - Come on!
我奶奶马上就要进手术室了
Grandma's gonna have to leave for the hospital soon!
就算你说的是真的
Even if what you were saying was true,
你也应该直接去借服装
you still should have asked for the mascot suit.
我有  我正大光明地问教练
I did. I asked Coach B if I could borrow the suit
我能不能借服装  可他不同意
fair and square, but he wouldn't let me.
大概是觉得我会在里面拉屎吧
Probably thought I was gonna poop in it.
因为我以前爱在各种东西里拉屎
Just 'cause I used to poop in stuff.
放弃吧  齐克  快到了  鲁迪
Give it up, Zeke. Almost there. Oh, Rudy.
蒂娜  你让我没得选了
Tina, you leave me no choice.
-福旺德老师  -不要啊
- Mr. Frond...! - No!
齐克  你应该在校长办公室啊
Zeke? You should be in the principal's office.
他本来在的  我刚送他去了
He was... um, 'cause I took him, obviously.
她没送  她没送
She never took him. She never took him.
蒂娜  是这样吗
Tina, is this true?
是的  你手机怎样了
Yes. How's your cell phone doing?
彻底坏了
It's dead.
听说放在米桶里不是可以...
Oh, I heard that rice thing, that that's supposed to...
我对你很失望  蒂娜
I'm very disappointed in you, Tina.
看来你不能胜任这个职务
Clearly you couldn't handle this responsibility.
把手指套解开
Now, un-trap your fingers.
说得轻巧
You say that like it's easy.
再来一次
Let's do it again!
-嘿  尔珀小姐  -嘿  蒂娜
- Hi, Ms. Selbo. - Hi, Tina.
-有谣传说你失宠了  -什么
- I heard a rumor that you were disgraced. - What?
瓦格斯塔夫服务台
Wagstaff front desk.
女士  请问你是
You're calling from where, ma'am?
优雅碎花养老院
The Elegant Doily Retirement Home?
就街边那家吧
Oh, that's right down the street.
有时你们的人会迷路走到这儿来
Sometimes your wanderers come here.
我不太清楚你孙子
Well, I don't know if your grandson
还会不会去看你  他叫什么
is still coming to visit-- who is he?
齐克啊  我看看能不能帮你找到他
Oh, Zeke. I'll see if I can find him for you.
齐克没撒谎
Zeke was telling the truth.
-永久通行证  -可以有限地为所欲为啦
- Perma-pass! - We can do anything we want within limits!
伙计们  听着  我欠你们一个道歉
Hey, uh, guys, listen, I owe you both an apology.
-那是  -我被野心蒙蔽了自我
- Yeah. - My ambition got the best of me.
它把我变成了一个不合格的巡视员
I've let it turn me into a bad hall monitor
和一个糟糕的姐姐
and an even worse sister.
是的  没错
Yes, you did.
对不起
I'm sorry.
-我们原谅你  -吉恩
- We forgive you. - Gene!
注意节奏
Leave her hanging for a second.
-我不接受道歉  -就是
- Shove your apology! - Yeah!
-我理解  -行了  我们原谅你
- That's fair. - Okay, okay. We forgive you.
谢谢
Ah, thank you.
还有一个事儿
And there's one more thing.
我们得帮帮齐克
We need to help Zeke.
蒂娜  我不想戳穿你
Tina, I hate to tell you this,
可那不是齐克
but that's not Zeke.
齐克在校长办公室
Okay, Zeke is in the principal's office
被舒娜和福旺德老师看着
being watched by Ms. Schnur and Mr. Frond.
校长每天会在他的车里午睡到一点四十五
The principal naps in his car every day until 1:45.
这样我们就有七分钟的时间救出齐克
That gives us seven minutes to spring Zeke.
我们要怎么过福旺德老师那关
How are we gonna get past Mr. Frond?
福旺德倒没啥  应该担心的是舒娜老师
Forget Frond-- it's Ms. Schnur you've got to worry about.
她人虽然矮  手臂却超长
She's short, but she's got a seven-foot wingspan.
没事  我有办法
It's okay. I have an idea.
我不说了吗  我奶奶要做手...
I told you, my grandma's about to go under...
别再拿你奶奶那套胡扯了
Spare me the grandma stuff.
奶奶这个借口都快比你奶奶还老了
Grandma excuses are older than grandmas themselves.
潘妮・马歇尔来我们学校了
Hey, Penny Marshall's outside!
美国女演员  导演  制片人
我的潘妮・马歇尔
The Penny Marshall?!
没错  她还说是来
Yeah. And she said something
找新朋友的
about needing a new best friend.
也许是我啊
That could be me!
舒娜老师  潘妮・马歇尔不可能来
Ms. Schnur, Penny Marshall is not outside.
福旺德老师  如果她来了  而我没去
Mr. Frond, if she is out there and I don't go out,
我这辈子都不会原谅自己的
I will never forgive myself!
-别挡路  -舒娜老师  不
- Out of my way! - Ms. Schnur, no!
齐克  快跑
Zeke, run!
过来  过来
Come here, get up.
-快辅导辅导我  -不  来辅导我
- Counsel me. - No, counsel me.
-现在没空  -辅导我  -辅导我
- Not now. - Counsel me! - Counsel me!
-我一团糟  -我是个大麻烦
- I'm messed up! - I'm a big mess!
齐克
Zeke.
怎么回事
What's going on?
-拿着  -什么
- Take it. - What?
-快走吧  -我去  蒂娜
- And go. - Damn, Tina.
这下我在我们的婚礼上可有故事讲了
Now I got a story to tell on our wedding day.
别以为那不可能
You think that's not gonna happen,
我会把你追到手的  姑娘
but I'll get you, girl.
我一定会的
I'm gonna get you.
好吧  别  啥都别说了  快走吧
Okay, d-don't say anything, just go.
齐克  回来
Zeke, come back here!
让他走  福旺德老师
Let him go, Mr. Frond.
他是去给他要做手术的奶奶打气的
He's going to see his grandma before she has surgery.
他奶奶
His grandma?
你真是个天真的大眼甜心小蠢蛋
You naive little wide-eyed candy-dandy fool.
我们说的是齐克好吗
This is Zeke we're talking about.
他曾经撒谎说自己长了虱子
Once, he faked lice.
还说自己看到了美人鱼啥的
I think he used Sea-Monkeys.
可她奶奶来电时我就在尔珀小姐办公室
But I was in Ms. Selbo's office when his grandma called.
随便找个人都能假扮他奶奶
Anyone can get a friend to pretend to be someone's grandma.
甚至有专门提供这种服务的行业
There are services that do that.
福旺德老师  我们是过道巡视员
Mr. Frond, we're hall monitors.
但人可不是过道
But people aren't halls.
你让达瑞尔・霍尔怎么想
Tell that to Darryl Hall.
前者为美国歌手  后者为演员
两者的姓氏"霍尔"与"过道"同音
还有安东尼・迈克尔・霍尔
And Anthony Michael Hall.
阿森诺・霍尔[演员]
Arsenio Hall.
好吧  很多人姓霍尔[过道]
Okay, a lot of people are Halls.
但我的意思是人是很复杂
But what I'm saying is people are complicated.
人生也很复杂
Life is complicated.
有时候  骗子也会说实话
And sometimes even liars tell the truth.
我相信齐克
I believe Zeke.
是吗
You do, huh?
好吧  我和你打赌  赌他在说谎
Okay, I'll bet you he's lying.
如果我错了  你就一点事没有
If I'm wrong, you're not in trouble.
好吧  豁出去了  我还给你升职
And, what the heck, I'll give you your promotion.
我不需要升职了
Forget the promotion.
如果你错了  就别让齐克休学
If you're wrong, Zeke's not suspended.
没问题  我还可以给齐克的假想奶奶
Sure, I'll even throw in some ice cream
买冰激凌庆祝她顺利通过假想手术
for Zeke's imaginary granny after her imaginary surgery.
你还得娶她  好赢得美国公民身份
And you have to marry her for citizenship.
如果蒂娜输了呢
What happens if Tina loses?
一个月的留校
One month's detention.
你还得上交背心
And you turn in your vest.
还有手指套
And your finger trap.
-可那是我的啊  -我赢了就是我的了
- But that's mine. - If I win, I want it.
这赌注不错  蒂娜
Cool bet, Tina.
但齐克可是惯犯
But Zeke does this kind of thing a lot.
这是我这个
And that's coming from a girl
惯犯给你的提醒
who does this kind of thing a lot.
是啊  蒂娜  再考虑考虑
Yeah, think about it, T.
放马来吧  福旺德
You're on, Frond.
好极了
Terrific.
去养老院
To the nursing home!
我们也去
We're coming, too.
-没错  -很好
- Yeah! - Great!
都来吧
Come along.
等  等等  你们这是去哪儿
W-wait, where's everybody going?
"让蒂娜被残酷现实狠狠地
We're going on a "Splash of cold hard truth
扇一记耳光"之旅
in Tina's face" Field trip!
我怎么都没有那样的待遇
I didn't get a slip for that.
"优雅碎花"养老院
好了  我们到了
Okay, here we are.
齐克奶奶
Zeke's grandma?
齐克的奶奶在吗
Is Zeke's grandma here?
我是
Yes.
是齐克奶奶  错不了
Yep, that is definitely Zeke's grandma.
真奇怪
Oh, that's strange.
齐克的奶奶在这儿  可怎么没见齐克呀
There's Zeke's grandma, but I don't see Zeke anywhere.
我看正是因为...
Maybe that's because--
骗子就是骗子  人心就是不可信
Liars are liars, and people are bad.
而我是对的
Buh, buh, buh, buh, buh, buh, I am right!
你是给我做手术的医生吗
Are you my surgeon?
齐克居然不在
I can't believe Zeke's not here.
真遗憾  蒂娜
Sorry, Tina.
我本来也挺希望齐克能来的
I was kind of hoping he would be here, too.
准备好了吗
Y'all ready for this?!
不不不不不不
No, no, no, no. No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
你输了  福旺德
You lose, Frond.
你输了
You lose!
捕鲸者的粉丝们
Whalers in the front!
让我听到你们的声音
Let me hear you grunt!
我的乖孙子
That's my boy.
冰激凌时间到啦
Ice cream time!
这附近就有
There's an ice cream truck
卖冰激凌的小摊  福旺德老师
around here somewhere, Mr. Frond.
去找找吧
Better go find it.
得得得  我去
Okay, okay, okay, I'm going.
用走的  别跑
Walk, don't run.
说得好
Nice!
你回来了
There you are.
你去哪儿了
Where were you?
你去商店了吗
Did you go to the store or something?
算是吧
I did, in a way.
我买了一个全新的自己
And what I bought was a new me.
一个能画画的自己
A me who can draw!
看哪  琳
Look at this, Lin.
裸体的伊迪丝
It's naked Edith!
画得不错
It's good.
孩子们  快看  是裸体的伊迪丝
Kids, look-- it's naked Edith.
-裸体的伊迪丝  -裸体的伊迪丝
- Naked Edith! - Naked Edith!
"垂垂"老矣  但久经风霜
Saggy and sophisticated.
正如她的车尾贴所说一样
Just like it says on her bumper sticker.
看我在干嘛
Oh, oh, look what I'm doing.
看  看我把它贴到哪儿了
Right now. Look, look where it's going.
-真的吗  -没错
- Really? - Yep.
我的画上墙了
I made the wall.
你的画让墙变性感了
You made the wall sexy.
看看那些褶子
Look at all those nooks and crannies.
是啊  好多好多层
Yeah, lotta-lotta folds.
捕鲸者的粉丝们
Whalers in the front!
让我听到你们的声音
Let me hear you grunt!
捕鲸者的粉丝们
Whalers in the front!
让我听到你们的声音
Let me hear you grunt!